castrolcricket.com 2009-06-29

# castrol cricket : Privacy Statement

## Information about our Organisation and Website 

Castrol respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it. We provide this Privacy Statement to inform you of our Privacy Policy and practices and of the choices you can make about the way your information is collected online and how that information is used. This website is governed in accordance with the laws of India. Only the courts of Mumbai, in India shall have exclusive jurisdiction over any dispute arising out of your use of this website.   
The [http://www.castrolcricket.com](http://www.castrolcricket.com/) website is owned by Castrol India Limited: 1st Floor Technopolis Knowledge Park, Mahakali Caves Road, Chakala, Andheri (E), Mumbai- 400093, India 

## Data automatically collected 

We log visitor’s domain and IP address automatically; this information does not identify you as an individual, but only the computer that is being used to view the website. This data is used to see where the website is being used in the world to ensure coverage, and for click stream analysis to help better understand site usage, so that we can improve our service to you. We do not link information automatically logged by such means with personal data about specific individuals.   
Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer as a result of visiting a web site. This allows the site to know that you have visited before and in some cases can be used to record your preferences. 

## Cookies

We use cookies to help us track usage patterns in order to improve and manage our sites   
There are two types of cookies used on this website: 

## Session Cookies

These are temporary cookies that only remain until your browser is closed. They are used by our web application in order to maintain the information relating to your transaction from page to page following any input, such as when a form is completed over several screens. 

## Web Analytics Cookies

These cookies are used to help us compile anonymous statistics in order to improve and manage our sites. An example of the information collected would be the path you used to gain access to the site and your patterns of browsing when navigating the site. Another example may be when we record your content preferences on the site to deliver customised content on future visits.  They are ‘persistent’ meaning they are not deleted when the browser is closed and expire after a period of 2 years unless you visit the same site within the 2 year period in which case the same cookie is refreshed and a new 2 year period begins. 

You can still use most of this site with cookies turned off. To stop cookies being placed on your terminal equipment refer to your specific internet browser. In a few cases blocking cookies may reduce the functionality of some sites or prevent access to them depending on your chosen browser options. 

Cookies can also easily be deleted through your specific internet browser, although this means your settings will not be retained. 

For further information visit [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). This link will take you to another website that is opened in a new window. BP is not responsible for the content of the [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) website.

## Data collection and use 

When you request information through this site, we may need to know some personal information about you. When emailing us, or subscribing for free news or information we need your e-mail address, name and other limited personal identifiers, typically name, address and contact number. If you chose to purchase information, goods, products or services, we will usually require some additional limited financial details. Your personal data will be processed to provide information, goods, products and services you request in the form that you require. If we require sensitive personal data then we will ensure that the collection and use is in strict accordance with the principles of data protection and data privacy of the applicable legislation set out below. 

We may use your information to keep you updated about Castrol products and services by email and may, in addition, share your information with companies which are Castrol Group companies so that they can contact you by email about the products and services that they offer.  We may also share your information with carefully chosen third parties so that they can contact you by email about the products and services that they offer.  We willonly do this if you have indicated that you are happy for us to do so when we first collect your personal information.  Emails that you receive from Castrol, Castrol Group companies or third parties will always give you the opportunity to opt out of receiving further emails.

We may also use your personal data for the following purposes: 

  * To ensure that content from this site is presented in the most effective manner for your and for your computer and to customise this site for you; 
 
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service and competitions on this site, when you choose to do so; and 
 
  * To notify you about changes to our service and this site. 

We may appoint third party organisations to assist us in providing you with the information, goods, products and services you request. In these circumstances, we will take steps to ensure that your personal information is held in strict accordance with our privacy policy and is only used for the purpose of fulfilling your request. 

Except as set out above, we will not pass your details to anyone else outside the Castrol Group without your permission. Since Castrol operates globally, the information you submit may be transferred outside of India. This and all other transmissions will remain secure and under our control. By clicking the ‘I accept’ button where you offer your information in return for information, goods, products and services, you consent to such a transfer.   
If we look to use your personal data for a new purpose, beyond what it was originally provided for, we will ask for your consent. You can choose to provide this consent in advance by indicating in the ‘opt-in’ box at the point that personal data is collected.

## Data retention 

Data is held for the lifetime your subscription is active for the purposes of contacting you effectively after which time it is depersonalised and non-identifiable. We do not collect any additional information about you otherthan that outlined above.

## Access to your personal data 

To enquire about accessing your personal data, or if you have any questions relating to Castrol’s data privacy policy please post it to the following address: Digital Marketing, Castrol India Ltd, : 1st Floor Technopolis Knowledge Park, Mahakali Caves Road, Chakala, Andheri (E), Mumbai- 400093, India.We will provide you with a readable copy of the personal data that we keep about you, within 40 days, although we will require proof of your identity before disclosing that data. We allow you to challenge the data that we hold on you and, where appropriate, you may have the data: erased, rectified, amended or completed. We reserve the right to refuse to provide our visitors with a copy of their personal data, but will give reasons for our refusal. You will be able to challenge our decision to refuse to provide you with a copy of your personal data.

## Children 

Castrol is committed to protecting the privacy needs of children and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online activities and interests. Castrol does not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 and Castrol does not target its websites to children under 13.

## Security 

We have implemented security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control that complies fully with data privacy & protection legislation appropriate to the jurisdiction applicable to the website. The security measures are designed to prevent unauthorised access, improper use or disclosure, unauthorised modification and unlawful destruction or accidental loss. At present we do not give visitors to our website the option of using a secure transmission method to send us their personal data.

## Hyperlinks 

The Castrol websites may provide links to third-party websites for your convenience and information. If you access those links, you will leave the Castrol website. Castrol does not control those sites or their privacy practices, which may differ from Castrol’s. We do not endorse or make any representations about third-party websites. The Castrol Privacy Statement does not cover the personal data you choose to give to unrelated third parties. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any company before submitting your personal information. Some third-party companies may choose to share their personal data with Castrol; that sharing is governed by that third-party company’s privacy policy.
